(1938年6月)
在1930年的这十年中
In the decade of the 1930s
即使是像梅乔克力斯这般的大城
Even the great city of Metropolis
也无法抵挡全世界衰退的冲击
was not spared the ravages of the worldwide depression
那时代充满了恐惧与迷惑
In the times of fear and confusion
通知大众的工作
the job of informing the public was the responsibility
就落在星球日报的身上了
of the Daily Planet
一份大都会的报纸
A great metropolitan newspaper
因其慈善及真实性所生之信誉
whose reputation for clarity and truth had become a symbol of hope
促使其成为大都会希望象征之所寄
for the city of Metropolis
(星球日报)
《超人》
这不是幻想
This is no fantasy
一望无际的想像不需要留意
No careless product of wild imagination
不需要 我的好友们
No my good friends
控诉必备的要件
these indictments
今日我向你们所提的
l've brought you today
系指你们个人所犯之叛国罪
specific charges listed herein against the individuals
以及妨害治安之罪行
their acts of treason Their ultimate aim of sedition
以上
These
均是无可否认之事实
are matters of undeniable fact
我要求你们念出
I ask you now to pronounce judgment
判决的内容
on those accused
对这些被告
On this
对这个无情的叛离者
this mindless aberration
他只想以暴力和破坏来表现其情感
whose only means of expression are wanton violence and destruction
对这个女人亚莎
On the woman Ursa
她对所有全体人类的曲解及不合理的仇恨心态
whose perversions and unreasoning hatred of all mankind
已经威胁到全体克普顿星球的儿童
have threatened even the children of the Planet Krypton
最后一位是查德将军
Finally General Zod
曾经是委员会信任的一员
Once trusted by this Council
仍然背叛维持克普顿星球的辩护
charged with maintaining the defense of the Planet Krypton itself
创造者希望对这种预谋
Chief Architect of this intended revolution and author of this insidious plot
重新建立一项秩序所作之革命加以摧毁
to establish a new order amongst us
好让自己仍然成为绝对之统治者
with himself as absolute ruler
我们已经听过证据了
You have heard the evidence
现在宣布判决的结果
The decision of the Council will now be heard
有罪
Guilty
本项表决具有敌意 乔艾尔
The vote must be unanimous JorEI
现在已经变成你的判决
It has therefore now become your decision
如果你希望的话 你就判我们有罪吧
You alone will condemn us if you wish
那你就要对我这件事负责了
and you alone will be held responsible by me
加入我们
Join us
大家过去都知道你不同意委员会
You have been known to disagree with the Council before
你的声音就新秩序而言是最重要的
Yours could become an important voice in the new order
但我的却是次要的
second only to my own
我给你一个机会 乔艾尔
I offer you a chance for greatness JorEI
接受吧加入我们
Take it Join us
你会在我面前屈服的 乔艾尔
You will bow down before me JorEI
我发誓 不管天长地久
I swear it No matter that it takes an eternity
你终会在我面前屈服的
You will bow down before me
你们两个 将来
Both you and then one day
还有你的子孙
your heirs
不
No
放我们出去 救我
Let us out of here Help me
原谅我 我会回来的
Forgive me forgive me l shall return
一个令人不快的职务 已被巧妙地完成了 乔艾尔
An unpleasant duty has been masterly performed JorEI
他们得到了他们应得的命运
They have received the fate they deserved
隔绝在幽灵区
Isolation in the Phantom Zone
一个永恒的活死人区
an eternal living death
但还是个活着的机会
A chance for life nonetheless
跟我们相反
As opposed to us
目前此种状况是自杀
It's suicide
不 更糟 是灭种
No it's worse it's genocide
我警告你 乔艾尔
Be warned JorEI
委员会已经对你奇怪的理论作过评估
The Council has already evaluated this outlandish theory of yours
我的朋友 你知道我既不是草率也不是冲动
My friends you know me to be neither rash nor impulsive
我也不是给你们粗野或不支持的声音
I am not given to wild unsupported statements
我告诉你们 我们必须马上撤离这个星球
and I tell you that we must evacuate this planet immediately
乔艾尔 你是克普顿星球 最伟大的科学家之一
JorEI you are one of Krypton's greatest scientists
是 不过凡德阿也是
Yes but so is VondAh
这不是他们问你问题的答案
I don't question your data
事实不容否认
The facts are undeniable
那是你的结论 但我认为不能苟同
It's your conclusions we find unsupportable
这个星球只剩下最多三十天就会爆炸
This planet will explode within 30 days
如果没意外的话
If not sooner
我告诉你克普顿星球依然会绕着轨道运转
I tell you Krypton is simply shifting its orbit
乔艾尔
JorEI
讲理一点
be reasonable
我的朋友
My friend
我从不曾如此 不讲理的人是你
I have never been otherwise This madness is yours
讨论到此为止
This discussion is terminated
委员会的心意已决
The decision of the Council is final
你如果想做任何对本星球不利
Any attempt by you to create
或散布令人忧惧之事
a climate of fear and panic among the populace
我们均将视为叛乱的行为
must be deemed by us an act of insurrection
你想用叛乱罪逮捕我
You would accuse me of insurrection
难道连珍视生命也变成一种罪
Has it now become a crime to cherish life
你会被遗忘在永无止尽的监禁
You would be banished to endless imprisonment
在幽灵区里
in the Phantom Zone
一个永恒的空间
The eternal void
只有你和你自己
which you yourself discovered
你会遵守委员会的判决吗
Will you abide by the Council's decision
我会保持沉默
I will remain silent
我和我太太
Neither I
都不离开克普顿星球
nor my wife will leave Krypton
你完成了吗
Have you finished
差不多了
Nearly
这是唯一的回答 诺拉
It's the only answer Lara
如果他还继续跟我们一起
If he remains here with us
他也会和我们一起死亡
he will die as surely as we will
但 为什么是地球 乔艾尔
But why Earth JorEI
他们很原始 落后我们几千年
They're primitives thousands of years behind us
他可以利用这种好处而活下去
He will need that advantage to survive
他们的大气压也可以
Their atmosphere will
保护他
sustain him
他会抗拒他们的地心引力
He will defy their gravity
他看起来会和他们类似
He will look like one of them
但是他不会成为他们的一分子
He won't be one of them
不
No
他的分子密度构造 会使他更强壮
His dense molecular structure will make him strong
他变得会很奇特 很不同
He'll be odd Different
他的速度会很快速 而且刀枪不入
He'll be fast Virtually invulnerable
变成孤立 一个人
Isolated Alone
他不会只有一个人
He will not be alone
他永远都不会是一个人
He will never be alone
输送到乔艾尔住房的电力 现在太多了
The energy input to JorEI's quarters is now in excess
我们的资料显示 损失是导因于错误使用
Our data indicates the loss is due to a misuse of energy
那就调查
Investigate
如果调查证明是正确的话呢
And if the investigation proves correct
他知道他会面对什么样的罚责
He knew the penalty he faced
他甚至也是这个委员会的一员
He even is a member of this Council
法律不容挑战
The law will be upheld
你会旅行到很远的地方 我的小凯尔
You will travel far my little KalEI
但我们永远不会离开你的
But we will never leave you
即使面对我们的死亡
Even in the face of our death
我们永远丰盛的生命
the richness of our lives
都将会是你的
shall be yours
我所拥有的一切 我所感受的一切
All that I have all that I've learned everything I feel
所有的一切和更多的
all this and more I
我都无条件的留给你 我的儿子
I bequeath you my son
你会将我带在身上
You will carry me inside you
在你的一生当中
all the days of your life
你将以我的力量转为你的力量
You will make my strength your own
经由你的双眼看到我的生命
see my life through your eyes
就如同经由我的双眼一般
as your life will be seen through mine
儿子成为父亲 父亲
The son becomes the father and the father
儿子
the son
这是所有
This is all I
我能够给你的 凯尔
all I can send you KalEI
停 停 停啊
Stop Stop stop
那里有一个爱因斯坦 称他的理论为相对论
which Einstein called his theory of relativity
在你面前隐藏在水晶球中的
Embedded in the crystals before you
是从数世纪以来
is the total accumulation of all literature and scientific fact
所有文化及科学的累积
from dozens of other worlds
延伸到28条银河系中
spanning the 28 known galaxies
早期的中国文学早已指出这些复杂的关系
Early Chinese writings point out the complex relationship between
这些复杂的平均值到最大的力量
By carrying this complex equation to its ultimate power my son
都将会让你目光所及
Chief among these powers will be your sight
力量所及 听力所及
your strength your hearing
能力所及 你的速度将会无限的快速
your ability to propel yourself at almost limitless speed
我们这个宇宙的早期 是一个星际战争下的流血产物
The early history of our universe was a bloody mosaic of interplanetary war
你经过的这六个银河系
Each of the six galaxies which you will pass through
各有它们自己的法律 因空间和时间的变异
contain their own individual law of space and time
你不能干涉人类的历史
It is forbidden for you to interfere with human history
那是什么？
What? What was that?
到底是怎么搞的？ 你要 你
Now wouldn't that beat all get out? Well you
爸
Oh Pa
哦 我的天
Oh my
这些年来 我一直衷心的
All these years as happy as we've been
祈祷上帝可以给我们一个孩子
how I've prayed the good Lord would see fit to give us a child
甜心 把那块抹布给我
Honey will you hand me that rag up there
你现在拿东西比较容易了 强纳森
You take things easy now
记住菲尔医生的话 有关你心脏的问题
Remember what Doc Frye said about that heart of yours
首先我们回家要做的第一件事
Now the first thing we've got to do when we get home is find out
就是找出这小孩的家人
who that boy's proper family is
他没有家人了 反正不在这儿就是了
He hasn't got any Not around here anyway
马莎 你想的跟我正在想的事一样吗？
Are you thinking what I think you are thinking?
你可以说这个小孩 是我在北达科塔表哥的孩子
We could say he's the child of my cousin in North Dakota
现在是孤儿了
and just now orphaned
哦 马莎强纳森 他只是个婴儿
Oh Martha Jonathan he's only a baby
马莎 你看到我们是怎么发现他的？
Martha now you saw how we found him?
马莎克拉克肯特 你有在听我说话吗？
Martha Clark Kent are you listening to what I'm saying?
强纳森
Jonathan
嘿 过来
Come on gang
来
Come on
是 但 打的真是太棒了
Yeah but that was a great game
哦 好的
All right
来呀 走了 各位 叠好你们的钢盔吧
Come on hustle Let's go Stack your helmets neatly
记得明天要将制服清洗干净 要让它们看起来
Remember about those uniforms cleaned and washed by tomorrow
像是支美式足球队一样
and looking like a football team
嘿 克拉克 我们明天的衣服都要洗好
Clark let's have those clothes washed and ready for tomorrow's game
要打倒芒特佛南高中
Got to beat Mount Vernon High
早点回家 可不可以帮个忙
Home early Can you give me a lift
拉娜
Lana
不要烦恼这些 我会一起收拾的
Don't bother with these I'll take them in with the other equipment
- 谢谢你 克拉克  - 没问题
- Thank you Clark  - Sure
听着 我们一票人要去玛莉艾伦家
Listen a whole bunch of us are going up to Mary Ellen's
听听音乐 你要来吗
Play some records Would you like to come
好呀
Sure
好像很好玩的样子
Sounds like it could be a lot of fun
肯特不能去 因为还有很多事要做
Kent can't make it Still got a lot of work to do
你在说什么 我刚刚堆完
What are you talking about I've just finished stacking
还有那些
All that
哦 布雷特
Oh Brad
嘿 来呀 拉娜
Hey come on Lana
我们走
Let's go
- 走啦 他得整理这些呢 - 再见 克拉克
- He has to clean up - Bye Clark
- 再见 拉娜  - 赶快整理吧 克拉克
- Bye Lana  - Clean this up Clark
我们走啦 拜 克拉克
Let's go 'Bye Clark
我们要去玛莉艾伦家了 明天见 克拉克
We're off to Mary Ellen's See you Clark
好了
All right
拜 克拉克
Bye Clark
明天见 再见
See you tomorrow Byebye
(平交道)
天啊 我看到那边一个男孩 跑得跟火车一样快
Mommy I saw a boy out there run as fast as the train
甚至更快
Faster even
露意丝雷恩 你想像力真丰富
Lois Lane you have a writer's gift for invention
我会帮你说好话的 可是 可是
I'll say that for you But
露意丝 看你的书
Lois please read your book
都没人相信我
No one ever believes me
你们看 是克拉克
Hey look there's Clark
他怎么会在这里
How come he's here
克拉克
Clark
你怎么会来的这么快
How did you get here so fast
我用跑的
I ran
跑
Ran huh
告诉你 他是个奇怪的人 我们走吧
Told you he was an oddball Let's get out of here
又在炫耀了 是吗？
Been showing off a bit haven't you Son?
我不是故意要炫耀的 爸
I didn't mean to show off Pa
只是大家都喜欢布雷特 我只是想玩弄他们而已
It's just that guys like that Brad I just want to tear them apart
是 我知道
Yeah I know
我知道不应该
Yeah I know I shouldn't
我知道你可以做很多令人惊讶的事情
Yeah I know you can do all these amazing things
有时候你是不想顾虑太多
and sometimes you think that you will just go bust
但是除非你可以对大家明讲
unless you can tell people about it
是 那就对了
Yeah That's right
如果我去玩足球 每次都可以达阵得分
I mean every time I get the football I can make a touchdown
是的 每次
That's for sure Every time
我是说如果有一个人做他可以做得到的事也是炫耀吗？
Is it showing off when somebody's doing the things he's capable of doing?
鸟能飞也是炫耀吗？
Is a bird showing off when it flies?
不 不 你听我说
No no Now you listen to me
当你第一次来到这里 我们以为别人会来把你带走
When you came to us we thought people would take you away
因为当我们发现你的能力之后
when they found out the things that you do
那的确让我们很担心
It worried us a lot
当一个人老了之后 想法不同了
Then when a man gets older and he thinks very differently
有些事对他而言就比较清楚
And things get very clear
我只知道一件事 儿子 你会在这里就是有其原因
And there's one thing I do know Son and that is you are here for a reason
我不知是谁的原因 或是什么原因
I don't know whose reason or whatever the reason is
也许是因为
maybe it's because
我不知道
I don't know
但我知道 绝不只是为达阵得分而已
But I do know one thing It's not to score touchdowns
谢谢 爸爸
Thanks Dad
爸 我们赛跑回家
I'll race you to it Yeah
你会吗
You will
来 加油来
Come on,Papa run,come on,move
加油 布朗 好耶
Go go Come on Hey Baron
哦 不
Oh no
强纳森
Jonathan
爸
Dad
不
No
强纳森
Jonathan
不
No
这些能力
All those things I can do
让我可以做所有的事
all those powers
但我却无法救他
and I couldn't even save him
克拉克 起床啰
Clark get up
早安啊 斯麦利
Good morning Smiley
克拉克 吃早餐啰
Clark breakfast
你打算睡一整天吗
Are you going to sleep all day
克拉克 别这样 起床
Clark come on Get up
我要走了
I have to leave
我早知道此刻会到来
I knew this time would come
从发现你那天起我就知道了
We both knew it from the day we found you
我昨天和班哈巴谈过了
I talked to Ben Hubbard yesterday
他说 他从现在起愿意来帮忙
He said that he'd be happy to help out from now on
母亲
Mother
我了解 儿子
I know Son
我了解
I know
你知道你要往那儿去吗
Do you know where you're headed
北方
North
要记得我们 儿子
Remember us Son
永远记得我们
Always remember us
我的儿子
My son
你不记得我了
you do not remember me
我是乔艾尔
I am JorEI
我是你父亲
I am your father
现在你快18岁了
By now you will have reached your eighteenth year
如果以地球的日子算的话
as it is measured on Earth
如果这样计算的话
By that reckoning
我早已死去几千年了
I will have been dead for many thousands of your years
我所知道
The knowledge
有关身体及历史的知识
that I have of matters physical and historical
已在你去新家的路上都给了你
I have given you fully on your voyage to your new home
这些都十分重要
These are important matters to be sure
但仍只是事实而已
but still matters of mere fact
有很多问题要问
There are questions to be asked
是你该去探寻的时候了
and it is time for you to do so
在这
Here in this
孤立的城堡中
this fortress of solitude
我们一起去找寻答案吧
we shall try to find the answers together
所以我的儿子
So my son
说话吧
speak
我是谁
Who am I
你的名字是凯尔
Your name is KalEI
你是克普顿星球唯一的生还者
You are the only survivor of the Planet Krypton
即使你是由人类扶养长大 你也不属于他们
Even though you were raised as a human you are not one of them
你有强大的力量 有一些是你
You have great powers only some of which you have
尚未发掘的
as yet discovered
跟我来吧 我的儿子
Come with me now my son
当我们突破地球的限制
as we break through the bars of your earthly confinement
在时间与空间中旅游 在六度空间中遨游
Traveling through time and space
你的力量可以超越那些凡人
Your powers will far exceed those of mortal men
但你不能干涉人类的历史
It is forbidden for you to interfere with human history
也不能用你的领导力去影响他们
Rather let your leadership stir others to
过几年后 我们会来试验人们的心
In the next year we shall examine the human heart
他们比你的还更脆弱
It is more fragile than your own
过去两年里
For the past two years
当我们飞越炎热的混乱
As we pass through the flaming
也就是你自己的银河系边缘
turmoil which is the edge of your own galaxy
我们即将进入红色克普顿星球的领域
we will enter the realm of the red Krypton sun
你的力量及营养来源
source of your strength and nourishment
最终引起了克普顿星球的毁灭
and cause of our eventual destruction
我的孩子 这个克普顿星球
The Planet Krypton my son
就是你的家
your home as it was
这一年我们会试验不同的道德观念
This year we shall examine the various concepts of immortality
以及他们的事实基础
and their basis in actual fact
所有知识的累积 都将延伸到28条银河系
The total accumulation of all knowledge spanning the 28 known galaxies
并藏于水晶之中 我均已传送给你
is embedded in the crystals which I have sent along with you
好好的研读它们 我的孩子
Study them well my son
在过去12年的学习中
and learn from them
我们早已超越逻辑的判断之外了
We've reasoned out logical judgments
在你回到你的银河系之后
By the time you return to the confines of your galaxy
必定已过去十二年了
twelve of your years will have passed
因为这个理由
For this reason among others
我为你选择了地球
I have chosen Earth for you
此刻 是你重新投入新世界的时刻了
It is now time for you to rejoin your new world
去服务全体人类吧
and to serve its collective humanity
当他们其中的一分子 凯尔
Live as one of them KalEI
去发现你尚未发掘的力量及能力
and discover where your strength and your power are needed
这些特殊的遗传 是你可以自豪的
But always hold in your heart the pride of your special heritage
他们可能会成为伟大的人 凯尔 他们很希望如此
They can be a great people KalEI they wish to be
他们只是缺乏光明 以照亮他们的路
They only lack the light to show the way
因为此一理由 他们可以培养成为优良的人格
For this reason above all their capacity for good
我把他们交给你
I have sent them you
我唯一的儿子
my only son
好 这里就是了 老兄 星球日报到了
Okay this is it mac the Daily Planet
新鲜的水果 小姐 要不要蕃茄啊
Fresh fruit Hey how about a tomato lady
新鲜水果 宝贝 怎么样啊
Fresh fruitHey baby how's it going
新鲜的水果和蔬菜
Hey fresh fruit and vegetables
趁新鲜快来买
Fresh fruit and vegetablesGet them while they're hot
看看这些蕃茄 很美吧？
Look at these tomatoes Aren't they beautiful?
(星球日报)
他干的不错 你今天早上有看他的文章吗？
He did a great job You see his article this morning
笑一个
Smile
流血这个词有几个T
How many T's in bloodletting
二个
Two
你在写什么 雷恩小姐
What are you writing
写一首春天的颂诗 杀戮怎么写
An ode to spring How do you spell massacre
M-A-S-S-A-C-R-E…
M-A-S-S-A-C-R-E...
谢了
Thanks
天啊 雷恩小姐 你怎能写出这么伟大的故事
Golly how come you get all the great stories
好记者 写不出伟大的故事 吉米
A good reporter doesn't get great stories
好记者写得出使他们伟大的故事
A good reporter makes them great
老编 这是个有关东方谋杀案的故事
Chief here's that story on the murder case
在第一页有大的标题 也许我的照片摆在
The way I see it it's a headline on the front page with my picture
强奸者的奸打错了 露意丝雷恩
There's only one P in rapist
对克拉克肯特说声你好
Lois Lane say hello to Clark Kent
告诉过你打错了 哈啰 雷恩小姐 你好
Hello Miss Lane how are
记得我的性与药的报导
Remember my expose on the sex and drug orgies
在公立养老院那一篇吗
in the senior citizens home
你好啊 吉米欧森 摄影师
How are you doing Jimmy Olsen photographer
嗨 克拉克肯特 很高兴认识你
Hi Clark Kent Nice to meet you
每件事都扯到了 有性 有暴力
It's got everything: Sex
以伦理的角度 我是指
violence the ethnic angle
那个女摔角手有外国口音
So does a lady wrestler with a foreign accent
肯特 你打开一下吧 好的 白先生
Kent can you open this Sure Mr White
这也许是一个连载题材的好基础
This could be the basis for a series of articles:
让无理性的杀戮成为理性 由露意丝雷恩撰写
Making Sense of Senseless Killings by Lois Lane
我是指我们有心理学家 有社会学家 我可以约见
We get psychologists sociologists interviews
露意丝 你只不过在写一些垃圾而已
Lois you're pushing a bunch of rinkydink tabloid garbage
星球日报有一个传统
The Daily Planet has a tradition
抱歉
Oh I'm sorry I'm sorry
哦 天呀 对不起 我不知道会喷成这样
I'm sorry I didn't mean to shake it up like that
当然不 露意丝
Of course not Lois
为什么有人会想让一个陌生人 看起来像个呆子
Why would any one want to make a total stranger look like a fool
我来拿
I'll take that
谢谢 对不起 白先生
Thanks I'm sorry Mr White
欧森 我是叫你来闲逛的吗
Why do I pay you $40 a week when I should have you arrested for loitering
去帮先生拿条毛巾来 肯特
Go get Mr a towel Kent
快 小子 快 好的
Move kid move Right Chief
我要黑的 不要糖 好 老编
Make mine black no sugar Right Chief
不要糖的
And don't call me sugar
当番红花开时
while the crocuses bloom
是的 老糖
Right Sugar
老大要咖啡 不加糖 我去拿柠檬茶
Chief wants coffee no sugar I'll take tea with lemon
露意丝 你何不带肯特先去见见其他人
Lois why don't you take Kent out to meet everybody huh
帮他介绍一下 这是他第一天来上班
Just introduce him around He's starting on the paper today
我会让他去城中采访一下
I'm giving him the City beat
老编
Chief
那是我的地盘
That's my beat
露意丝 克拉克肯特也许只是一个性情温和的记者
Lois Clark Kent may seem like just a mildmannered reporter
但不只是懂得尊重老编
but not only does he know how to treat his Chief with the proper respect
也不只是因为他精力充沛 而且平凡的格调
not only does he have a snappy punchy prose style
他是我从事这行四十年来
but he is in my 40 years
打字最快的打字员
in this business the fastest typist I have ever seen
哦 对不起 先生
That's great
你忘了我的文章
Here you forgot my article
对不起 白先生 我在想
Excuse me Mr White I was wondering
你是否可以 每星期将我薪水的一半
if you could arrange for half my salary
寄到这个地方去
to be sent to this address on a weekly basis
你的老家吗
Your bookie right
我的什么
My what
不要告诉我
Don't tell me
他是送支票给他 那位甜美灰发的妈妈
He sends a check every week to his sweet grayhaired mother
事实上是银发
Actually she's silverhaired
好的 我会办的
I'll see what I can do
谢谢你 白先生
Thank you very much Mr White
对不起
Excuse me
这真的
Well
像在家吗
Any more at home like you
不像 一点也不像
Not really no
我想也是
I didn't think so
你的桌子在这边
Well get yourself a desk over here
在这儿
Over here
是的 这儿有一些纸张和档案
Here there's some paper and a file right there
对不起 对不起
Sorry
嗨 我是比尔布利森 嗨 我是克拉克肯特
Hi Bill Breesen Hi Clark Kent
很高兴见到你 欢迎加入我们
Nice to meet you Welcome aboard
这是你的毛巾 克拉克先生 是肯特
Here's your towel Mr Clark Kent
- 什么？  - 是肯特
- What?  - Kent
克拉克肯特 你是吉米欧森
Clark Kent Jimmy Olsen
对 那很棒 那你
Yeah lt's fantastic So you
对 我曾见过这家伙 太棒了
I met this really great guy you know Hey fabulous
对 很棒 我在那个牧场遇到他
We had this fabulous weekend I met him at this dude ranch
我有说过我以前 有
l used to ride Yeah
我11岁以后就没骑过了
I haven't been since I was seven
我要去寄这些信了 好 再见 祝你今晚好运
I got to mail these letters Good luck tonight
- 嗨 克拉克  - 嗨 露意丝
- Hi Clark  - Hi Lois
你上班的第一天觉得如何啊
How did you like your first day on the job
上班的时数 比我想像的要长一点
The hours were sort of longer than I expected
但就整体而言 能和你 吉米欧森和白先生见面
but on the whole meeting you and Jimmy Olsen and Mr White
我要说很突出
Gosh on a whole I'd say it's been swell
很突出 是
Swell Yup
你知道吗 克拉克
You know Clark
地球上很少人会
there are very few people left in the world
习惯说这个词
who feel comfortable saying that word
什么词 突出
What word Swell
真的吗 我一直认为这样说很自然
Really I always thought it was kind of natural
对不起 克拉克
Sorry Clark
不要担心
lt's all right
- 对不起 露意丝  - 哦 嗨雷斯
- Sorry Lois  - Hi Rex
哦 露意丝
Oh Lois
- 你今天好吗  - 直到看到你为止才好
- Did you see anything good today  - Not until you came along
哦 露意丝
Oh Lois
哦 雷斯 这位是
Rex this is
克拉克肯特 你好 拜
Clark Kent How do See you around
露意丝
Lois
嘿 你去哪儿
Hey where you going
帮你拿大衣
Can I help you with your coat
哦 好 谢了
Thanks Can you get that Sure
你喜欢白先生吗
Did you like Mr White
我认为他是个好人 吉米欧森也很不错
He was a nice guy and Jimmy was fantastic
嘿 来这儿
Come here Come on
来 来啊 进来 快 来啊
Get in here hurry up Come on
克拉克 我们最好快离开这里
We'd better get out of here
我想最好是照他的话做 露意丝
We'd better do what he says Lois
来 快进去 快
Come on get in here quick
不 不要 就这样 我们来了
Don't don't do anything It's all right I'm coming
我们来了
We're coming
对不起
Excuse me
继续 退到那里去
Go on back there
这里
Here Yeah yeah
拜托 别指着我 你会伤到人的
Don't point that at me sir You could hurt somebody with that
好啦
Yeah yeah
- 好了 好了  - 站住
- Okay okay  - Hold it there
等一下 先生
Just a minute
我当然明白
Now I realize that
有时候日子很难过 尤其是这几天 但是这不是答案
times are tough for some these days but this isn't the answer
你不能用枪解决社会问题
You can't solve society's problems with a gun
你知道吗 兄弟 你说对了
You know buddy you're right
- 我要开创新的一页  - 很好 先生 不错的想法
- I'm going to turn over a new leaf  - Good for you sir That's the spirit
看吧 他并不是有意要伤害别人
He doesn't really want to hurt anyone
等我拿了她的皮包之后
Right after I rip off this lady's purse
好
Of course
来 小姐 丢过来
Now come on lady hand it over
露意丝 我想你最好
Lois I think you'd better
露意丝 你在干嘛？
Lois What are you doing?
克拉克克拉克
Clark Clark
克拉克
Clark
你还好吗 克拉克
Are you all right? Clark
怎么了？
What happened?
- 天啊 我想我大概晕过去了  - 晕了？
- Golly I guess I must have fainted  - Fainted?
- 你晕了  - 对不起
- You fainted  - I'm sorry
突出
Swell
说真的 露意丝 假使那个人伤了你
Really Lois supposing that man had shot you
你真的值得为了十元
Is it worth risking your life over $10
两张信用卡 一把梳子和一支口红牺牲吗
two credit cards a hairbrush and a lipstick
- 你怎么知道？  - 知道什么？
- How did you know that?  - Know what?
你刚刚很正确的 描述我皮包中的东西
You described the exact contents of my purse
随便猜猜
Wild guess
计程车
Taxi
- 嘿  - 嗨 欧提斯
- Hey  - Hi Otis
发生什么事 伙伴
So what's happening partner
看看我们发现什么
Look what we got
我们把他拿下
Let's take him
等一下
Wait a minute
也许他会带我们去找那位大人物
Maybe he'll lead us to the big man himself
莱克斯路德
Lex Luthor
说对了 亚瑞摩斯
You got it Aramus
午夜我们就会抓到他了
We'll make Captain by midnight
你在读什么 XK101要测验了
Hey what do you read XK101 rocket to be used
你在读什么
Hey what do you read
- 嘿 马特  - 嘿 欧提斯
- Hey Matt  - Hi Otis
来买一份星球日报
Just getting a Daily Planet here
你在读什么？
Hey what do you read?
好好
Okay All right
我正在付钱给他 我也拿了饼干
See I'm paying him and I got a pretzel too
谢谢 欧提斯
Thanks Otis
好 多少包 舒兹
How many bags Shutzy
这里是大都会46 我们准备行动了 结束
This is Metropolis 46 We're on foot Over and out
我们走
Let's go
请注意
Your attention please
大都会飞行号已准备开车
The Metropolis Flyer is now ready for departure
在上层的6号月台 将在新洛雪停留
on the upper level Track 6
他要下火车月台 我跟踪他下去
He's going down on a train platform I'm going after him
好 哈利 我叫支援 小心 好吗
Okay I'll call for backup Be careful now will you
请上车
All aboard please
好的 亚瑞摩斯
All right Aramus All right
现在由下层上车
Now boarding on the lower level
十分钟 大家快来 冷气车
Now 10 minutes airconditioned cars
往芒特佛南 波基思 葛兰卡尼斯
Mount Vernon Poughkeepsie
请上车 全部上车
Board now All aboard
旅客转车处 到水牛城 雪城
Metropolis Transportation to Buffalo Syracuse
吸烟车往前走 请往前
Smoking cars are forward move along now
行李放在上头
Luggage at the top
吸烟车往前 上车 全部上车
Smoking cars are forward All aboard boarding
亚瑞摩斯 到22号轨道去
Aramus Aramus make it Track 22
我看到他了 我马上就来了 下层 22号轨道
I've seen him and I'm right on him Lower level Track 22
原来是这样呀
So that's it
真是太妙了 一个人动脑筋
It's amazing that brain can generate
就可以使他们的腿移动
enough power to keep those legs moving
哈利
Harry
哈利 你在哪里 哈利
Harry where are you Harry
不
No
哈利
Harry
变态
Sick
变态 你真的是变态
Sick you're really sick
我是变态 黛丝玛克小姐
I'm sick Ms Teschmacher
当我们开始实践全国性犯罪时 就已经变态了
Sick when we're days from executing the crime of the century
不离远一点 拜托
No no no Step away from that please
你要怎么庆祝 这犯罪的伟大时刻
How do you choose to congratulate the greatest criminal mind of our time
你看得出来我很聪明吗
Do you tell me that I'm brilliant
哦 不 那太简单了
Oh no that would be too obvious I grant you
有魔力
Charismatic
坏到极点的天赋
Fiendishly gifted
试试偏执这个词吧
Try twisted
走开走开
Get away from that get away
告诉我 莱克斯
Tell me Lex
为什么这么多人 在这个世纪 要因为犯罪而去受死
Why do so many people have to die for the crime of the century
为什么 你问我为什么
Why You ask why
为什么每次你在上厕所时 电话总是会响
Why does the phone always ring when you're in the bathtub
为什么最聪明的魔鬼领导人
Why is the most brilliantly diabolical leader of our time
围绕在他身边的却是一群呆子
surrounding himself with total nincompoops
我回来了 路德先生
I'm back Mr Luthor
是的 我正想跟你说话
I was just talking about you
你又被跟踪了
You were followed again
受不了这些像猫的反射动作
In spite of those catlike reflexes
路德先生 对不起
Mr Luthor I'm sorry
那是我要的报纸吗
Is that the newspaper I asked you to get me
是
Yes
为何我没有在读呢
Then why am I not reading it
因为我还没有给你
Because I haven't given it to you yet
对
Right
至少 这是官方的消息
At last it's official
谢谢你们对美国政府的慷慨帮助
Thanks to the help of the US Government
我们已经涉入最大的不动产骗局之中
we are about to be involved in the greatest realestate swindle of all time
莱克斯 这是什么不动产的观念
Lex what is this
无论何时 土地都会被提及
obsession with real estate All the time land land land
黛丝玛克小姐 我六岁时我父亲曾对我说
When I was 6 years old my father said to me
滚出去
Get out
在他说那句之前 儿子 股票有起有落
Before that he said Son stocks may rise and fall
公共设施及交通系统 也许会崩溃
utilities and transportation systems may collapse
人们也不好 但他们就是需要土地
people are no damn good but they'll always need land
而且他们会付出很高的代价
they'll pay through the nose to get it
记得我父亲说 土地
Remember my father said Land
没错
Right
很可惜 他当时的筚路蓝缕
It's a pity that he didn't see
无法看到我如今所创立的王国
from such humble beginnings how I've created this empire
- 一个王国  - 这个吗？
- An empire  - This?
黛丝玛克小姐 你认识多少位小姐
How many girls do you know have
是谁住在这条公园街大道里的
a Park Avenue address like this
公园大道 在200尺地底下的公园大道
Park Avenue address 200 feet below
你知道多少人有那样的大楼
Do you realize what people are shelling out up there
有那么多可怜的小房间 却要共用一个电梯
for a few miserable rooms off a common elevator
夫复何求
What more could anyone ask
- 欧森  - 是
- Olsen  - Yeah
把朗奇奈斯马上排版好吗
Get this Loch Ness update right into composing
是 够了 罗丝 放回床上 好吗
Yeah No that's it Roth Put it to bed Right
- 你站在那儿干嘛  - 我没有
- Why are you standing here for  - I'm not
- 我没有要说的  - 去
- I wasn't going to say it  - Go
这个性变态的档案
The sex maniac profile
对 九点到五点
Right Nine to five it's a Pulitzer
这就是普立兹奖的得主 要不要打赌
Prize winner What do you bet
没有奶罩的罩打错了
There's no Z in brassiere
你对那件丑闻处理得很好 肯特
Nice job on that union scandal Kent
天呀 谢谢 白先生
Gosh thanks Mr White
嗨 克拉克 晚安
Hi Clark Good night
- 来 我来帮你拿  - 非常谢谢你
- Here let me carry that for you  - Thanks a lot
露意丝 你有空吗
Lois have you got a minute
对不起 露意丝
Excuse me please
这两个地址要打上去 好吗
And these two go to the addresses on the envelope okay
露意丝 我猜想你也许想跟我吃个晚餐
I was wondering if you'd have dinner with me
天呀 克拉克 对不起 我已有约了
I'm sorry I'm booked
空军一号已降落在机场 这个小子想去那里
Air Force One is landing at the airport This kid 'll be there to make sure
要确定你知道是谁
you know who answers
会回答一些问题 我宁愿他回避
the questions he would rather duck
拜托 你不能放轻松一下吗
Don't you ever let up
为什么 我已经看过另一半的人的生活
What for I mean I've seen how the other half lives
举例来说 我妹妹要处理三个小孩
My sister for instance Three kids
两只猫 一个贷款
two cats and one mortgage
我一个礼拜怎么够用
I would go bananas in a week
- 我能带你去机场吗？  - 除非你能飞
- Can I take you to the airport?  - Not unless you can fly
- 哦 克拉克 女士专用  - 对不起
- Ladies  - Sorry
我必须换衣服 谢谢 再见
Change my clothes. Thank you Bye
不 等等 露意丝 也许我们可以
Hey Lois maybe we could
(女士)
露意丝
Lois
- 你可不可以行行好帮我寄一下 谢谢  - 哦 好
- Would you mail that for me? thanks  - Sure
晚安
Good night
哦 哦 下去吗 麻烦了
Going down please going down
(编辑室)
下去吗
Going down
上去 上去
Going up Up up
晚安
Good night
这是地面一号
Daily Planet Copter One This is ground
行星一号请直走
Planet One go ahead
雷恩小姐在这要搭便机前往大都会机场
Miss Lane is here for a
采访空军一号 我们在赶时间
ride to the airport to meet Air Force One It's a hurry flight
了解 我们已经过河 看到你们了
We're on our way over the river
有一个人准备好要上飞机了 完毕
Have one aboard for transfer Over
收到 星球一号 你可以安全降落
Roger Planet One You're clear to land
风向02015 阵风 测高2989
Wind 02015 Altimeter 2989
收到 完毕
Roger Over and out
(星球日报)
我们被勾到了 没办法升空
A malfunction can't get lift off
- 你勾到钢索了  - 发生什么事 怎么了
- You've hooked a cable  - What's happening
下降 下降
Set it down
天呀 引擎系统失去控制了
My God we've lost motor control
我无法控制
I can't hold it
我无法控制了
失控了
He's lost it
醒醒
Wake up
救命
Help
哦 天呀 救命
Help Help
退后 大家
Step back folks
大家退后 退到马路那一边去
Get back Move over to the other side of the street
摄影机过来拍上面
Bring the canvas here Get it up there
直升机在上面
There's helicopter up there
救命
Help me
退后 让救护车可以通过
All right folks Let's move back
有人在上面
Let these firemen get in here
救我
Help me
等等 退后
Hold it Get back
到另一边去 快点 退后
Get off the street folks
让消防队员可以进来
Move let the firemen through
快点 围起来
Boys come on now Make a line
移到马路另一边去
Move to the other side of the street
沿着那儿 沿着建筑物的另一边
All right get along there Get away from the side of the building
(公共电话)
让群众退后 快呀
Hold these crowds back Move
救命
Help
嘿 老兄
Say Jim
对不起
Excuse me
那服装真逊
That's a bad outfit
好了 叫这些人离开
Okay move these people
天呀 看看上面
Oh my God Look up there
那到底是什么
What the hell's that
放轻松 小姐 我抱住你了
Easy miss I've got you
你 你抱住我？ 那谁抱住你？
You've got me? Who's got you?
我不敢相信 我真的不相信 他救到她了
I can't believe it I just cannot believe it He got her
(星球日报)
先生 这个人需要帮助
Gentlemen this man needs help
我希望这小小的意外 不会耽误你的飞行
I hope this little incident hasn't put you off flying miss
依统计上来说 这当然仍是最安全的飞行
Statistically speaking of course it's still the safest way to travel
对
Right
等等
Wait
你是谁？
Who are you?
一个朋友
A friend
拜
'Bye
你好啊 这儿的电梯出问题了
Something wrong with the elevator
往下
Going down
警官
Officer
晚上好 慕尼警官
Good evening Officer Mooney
他们说忏悔对灵魂有益
They say confession is good for the soul
我会听听这个人忏悔的 带他走
I'd listen to this man Take him away
快 我们离开这
Come on let's get out of here
动作快点 快呀
Move your ass Come on
我们走
Okay let's go Let's go
放下你们的武器
Drop your weapons Drop your weapons
滚你的 快 我们快离开
Bullshit Come on let's get out of here
站在那别动
Okay hold it Hold it right there
好的 停住你们两个
Okay freeze you turkeys
别开枪 别激动 你抓着我们了
Don't shoot Keep your cool You got us
感觉如何
Bad vibrations
长官 你不会相信 我发誓 他真的会飞
Sergeant you don't believe me I swear it flying
穿红披风 蓝色衣服
With a big red cape and bright red boots as well
转眼间就来到我面前
Quick as a wink he was gone
然后又瞬间离去 就像一只大鸟
He flew up in the air again he did like a big blue bird
大鸟 你不相信
A big blue bird You don't believe me
穿着明亮的红披风
With bright red boots
划破漆黑的夜空
Take the night off
回你的莫菲酒吧继续你的胡编乱造去吧
Go back to Murphy's bar and continue what you started
我过几分钟就会去找你的
I'll be off in a few minutes and I'll meet you there
慕尼 第一瓶酒我请 我去拿帽子
The first bottle's on me Let me get my hat
布斯基 快从那里下来
Frisky will you come down from there
嗨 我来帮你
Hi I'll get him
来吧 没关系的
Come on it's all right
来了 小姐 谢谢 先生
Here you go miss Gee thanks mister
不客气 再见 布斯基
Goodbye Frisky So long now
再见
'Bye
妈妈 妈妈 刚才布斯基爬到树上
Mommy Mommy Frisky was stuck in the tree
有个人从天上飞下来把它给了我
Then this man swooped out of the sky and gave him to me
我告诉过你少给我撒谎
Haven't I told you to stop telling lies
首都机场 这里是空军一号
Metropolis Airport this is Air Force One
请通报最新的天气情况
Could we have the latest weather report
因为暴风雨可见度较低 可视范围500尺
Metropolis currently ceiling 500 overcast 700 broken
风力24025 高度9098
visibility one half in showers Wind 24025 Altimeter 9098
收到
Roger
看起来不太好 你认为呢
Doesn't look good, What do you think
- 该死的怎么了  - 一号马达失去动力
- What the hell was that  - You've lost power in number one
失去动力 那整个动力系统就完了
Lost power We've lost the whole engine
电力不足 关闭一号马达
Pressure's going Shut down number one
加强二号和三号动力
Bring up two and three
我们缺少继续运作的动力
We haven't got enough pressure to keep going
紧急求救 紧急求救 首都机场 这里是空军一号
Mayday mayday Metropolis tower Air Force One
我们出现了马达故障 现在正在失速中
We have lost port outboard engine and part of wing
需要紧急迫降 什么方位？
Request emergency landing, What's the position?
机场西南方10里处
Ten miles southwest of Metropolis Airport
通知他们总统在飞机上
Notify them the President's on board
机场西南方10里处
Present position 10 miles that's 10 miles southwest of Metropolis Airport
方向是306度 高度6000尺
Heading: 305 height: 6000 feet
又怎么了？ 引擎又好了？
What the hell happened? We got our engine back?
外面到底怎么回事？
What the hell's going on out there?
驾驶 别乱看 继续驾驶就行了
Fly don't look just fly
我们得到一种力量的帮助
We got something
别问我是什么 只管相信我
I'm not saying what it is just trust me
你乐在其中
You enjoyed it
我不知道你说什么 父亲
I don't know what to say Father
抱歉我分心了
I am afraid just got carried away
我知道你会这样 吾儿 怎么可能
I anticipated this my son You couldn't have
你无法想像
You couldn't have imagined
那感觉有多好
How good it felt
全世界都知道你了
You are revealed to the world
很好
Very well
就这样吧
So be it
但你还是要保持身分的秘密
But you still must keep your secret identity
为什么
Why
原因有二
The reasons are two
第一 你没办法28小时拯救人类
First: You cannot serve humanity 28 hours a day
- 二十四  - 喔 二十四
- Twenty-fourth  - Wow twenty-fourth
那是地球的时间
As it is it won't happen
他们会一直求救
Your help will be called for endlessly
即使是那些人类自 就可以解决的问题
Even for those tasks that human beings can solve themselves
因为他们喜于滥用资源
They're happy to abuse the resources of the world
第二呢？
And secondly?
第二
Secondly:
你的敌人将会发现
Your enemies will discover
唯一能伤害你的方法
their only way to hurt you
就是伤害你在乎的人
by hurting the people you care for
谢谢你 父亲
Thank you Father
最后
Lastly:
不要因为感到自负而自责
Do not punish yourself with your feelings of vanity
只要学着控制它就好
Simply learn to control them
这是个普世皆同的烦恼 即使在克普顿星球也一样
It is an affliction common to all even on Krypton
我们的毁灭本可避免 如果不是一些自负者
Our destruction could have been avoided but for the vanity of some
以为我们是不可毁灭的
who considered us indestructible
如果不是为此
Were it not for vanity
此时此刻
at this very moment
可便可以将你拥入怀中
I could embrace you in my arms
吾儿
my son
报导说出现一个奇迹救了空军一号
Reports are coming in of a miraculous saving of Air Force One
可以了解的
from almost certain destruction
红披肩 蓝服装的人物 救了露意丝雷恩小姐
Rescuing Miss Lois Lane reporter from
他在星球日报一手抱住她
the Daily Planet with one hand
一手则是
and a crashed helicopter with the other
是啊 那就是梦想成真的一天
That'll be the day
我是说 如果人可以飞 那真是梦想成真了
That'll be the day when a guy could fly
我不知道 你说不定会很惊喜
I don't know You would be surprised
也许有某些奇妙的恶作剧
Some sort of fantastic hoax
你的猜测如同别人一样 错误或真实
Your guess is as good as anybody's True or false
是奇迹还是骗局
Miracle or fraud The answer
答案就由您来决定 黛丝玛克小姐
Miss Teschmacher Man or myth
把它关掉
Turn it off
莱克斯 这个家伙是谁
What's the story on this guy
你认为这报导是真实的吗
Do you think it's the genuine article
如果是 他一定不是这个世界上的人
If he is he's not from this world
为什么
Why
因为有任何人想做这种奇妙的恶作剧的话
If any human being was gonna perpetrate such a hoax
那一定是我
it would have been me
欧提斯 我的浴袍
My robe
马上来 路德先生
Right away Mr Luthor
一切都很巧 他来大都会
It all fits somehow this coming here to Metropolis
尤其是此刻
and at this particular time
这是一种残忍的正义
There's a kind of cruel justice about it
我是指世纪性的犯罪
To commit the crime of the century
一个人会想去面对世纪的挑战
a man wants to face the challenge of the century
听着 路德先生 也许这个飞人才刚刚飞过呢
Listen maybe this guy that flies is just sort of passing through
你知道吗
You know
飞过
Passing through
不会发生在你有生之年 欧提斯
Not on your life Otis
我很愿意牺牲
which I would gladly sacrifice by the way
如果有机会 去摧毁他所代表的一切
for the opportunity of destroying everything that he represents
欧提斯 下次在我走出浴池后
And Otis by the way next time put my robe on after
再放下我的浴袍
I'm out of the pool
看
Now look
邮报 说是飞人
The Post It Flies
新闻报导看 没有钢丝
The News Look Ma No Wires
时代杂志说 蓝色炸弹骚动大都会
The Times Blue Bomb Buzzes Metropolis
星球日报 我们正安坐于世纪故事的顶端
The Planet We're sitting on top of the story of the century here
我想知道这个飞人的名字
I want the name of this flying whatchamacallit
他和星球日报的关系密切
to go with the Daily Planet like bacon and eggs
就像坦白和阴沉 死亡与节制 政治和堕落
franks and beans death and taxes politics and corruption
我不认为他会把
I don't think that he'd
自己的故事 廉价出卖给记者写 白先生
lend himself to any cheap promotion schemes
你怎么知道 肯特
Exactly how would you know that
只是觉得会这样
Just first impression
无论如何 谁说会是廉价
Who's talking cheap
如果我要的话 会找他当合伙人,对吧？
I'll make him a partner if I have to, Right?
对 老编
Right Chief
我要真的故事
I want the real story
我要这人的真实事迹
I want the inside dope on this guy
他有无家庭 他住那儿？ S是代表什么？
Has he got a family Where does he live? What does the S stand for?
今晚八点在你家 希望 一个朋友
Tonight at 8:00 Your place Hopefully A friend
他怎么飞
How does he fly
一个朋友
A friend
汤尼 他是谁？ 麦克 他叫什么名字？
Tony who is he? Mike what's his name?
为何他要隐藏在斗篷之下 有电池吗？
What's he got hidden under that cape Batteries?
为何昨晚会出现？
Why did he show up last night?
迪克 他打那儿来？
Where does he come from?
他有女朋友吗？
Does he have a girlfriend?
他最喜欢的球队是哪个？ 肯特
What's his favorite ball team? Kent
听我说 我告诉你们
Now listen to me I tell you boys and girls
不管你们哪个能挖到他的新闻
whichever one of you gets it out of him
都会是自从上帝跟摩西说过话之后
is going to wind up with the single most important interview since
最重要的访问
God talked to Moses
还站在那儿干嘛？ 去啊
What are you standing around about for? Move.
把访问给我带回来
Get on that story
八点钟 他说八点钟 八点钟 某个朋友
8:00 he said Some friend
那是我的生活故事 灰姑娘要变公主了
That's the story of my life Cinderella Bites The Dust
晚安 雷恩小姐
Good evening, Miss Lane
对不起 今晚有约会吗
I am sorry, Did you have plans this evening
没事 没有
This old thing No
- 听着 我晚一点回来没关系  - 不
- I could come back later  - No
不要动
Don't move
你当然可以动
Sure you can move
但不要飞走 好吗
Just don't fly away all right
对不起 担搁你的时间 但我一直在想
Sorry to drop in on you like this but I've been thinking
你知道 一定有很多关于我的疑问
but there must be a lot of questions about me
世界上的人都想知道答案
There must be some questions people'd like to know the answers to
当然 是的
Of course yes
你不应该吸烟的 你知道吗 雷恩小姐
You really shouldn't smoke
不要告诉我 肺癌 好吗
Don't tell me Lung cancer right
还没 谢谢上帝
Well not yet thank goodness
你要不要来杯酒？
Would you like a glass of wine?
不 谢谢 我飞的时候不喝酒
No thanks I never drink when I fly
很好的地方
Nice place
谢谢
Thank you
我们可以开始访问了吗
Shall we get started with the interview
哦 谢谢
Thank you
让我从重要的事情开始问 你结婚了吗？
Let's start with your vital statistics, Are you married?
不 没有
No I'm not
有没有女朋友？
Do you have a girlfriend?
没有 但
No I don't But
如果我有 雷恩小姐会第一个知道的
If I did you'd be the first to know about it
- 你几岁？  - 超过21岁
- How old are you?  - Over 21
喔 我了解了 你不要别人知道
I get it You don't want anyone to know
好 你多大？ 你多高？
And how big are you? How tall are you?
六尺四寸
About 6' 4
六尺四寸 你多重？
6' 4 And how much do you weigh?
225磅
Around 225
我想
I assume then that
你身体其他的功能都正常吗
the rest of your bodily functions are normal
对不起 再说一遍
I beg your pardon
这样说好了
Well putting it delicately
你吃
do you...
东西吗？
...eat?
是的 我饿的时候
Yes I do when I'm hungry
当然 你会
You do Of course you do
你能看穿一切东西
Well then is it true...
是真的吗？
...that you can see through anything?
是的 可以看很多
Yes I can pretty much
你对于痛完全没有感觉吗
And that you're totally impervious to pain
还好
Well so far
我穿着什么样的内衣？
What color underwear am I wearing?
对不起 我让你不好意思 不是吗？
Did I embarrass you?
- 哦 不  - 我有
- No  - I did
这道墙是铅盖的
No it's just that this planter must be made of lead
是的 的确 所以呢
Yes it is So
你知道 我我无法透视铅
I sort of have a problem seeing through lead
真好玩
That's interesting
无法透视铅
Problems with lead
你的名字叫什么？
Do you have a first name?
你的意思是说 叫罗夫或什么的？
Like Ralph or something?
- 不 我的意思是说  - 粉红色
- No I mean like  - Pink
粉红色
Pink
对不起 我不是故意要让你不好意思
Sorry I didn't mean to embarrass you
你并没有
You didn't embarrass me
你的背景呢？ 你是那里人？
What's your background? Where are you from?
事实上有点难说明
It's kind of hard to explain actually
我从很远很远的地方来的
You see I'm from Well from pretty far away
事实上 来自另一个银河系
Another galaxy as a matter of fact
我来自一个叫克普顿星球的地方
I come from a planet called Krypton
克普顿
Krypton
哦 克普顿是要怎么写？C-R-I…
Cripton With a C-R-I...
不 事实上克普顿 是巧克力的克 普通的普
No actually it's Krypton with a KRYPTON
克普 你喜欢粉红色吗
Do you like pink
我非常喜欢
I like pink very much
为什么？
Why are you?
对不起
Sorry
我是指你为何在此？ 一定有什么理由让你来此
I mean why are you here? There must be a reason for you to be here.
是 我是来此为真理及正义 并以美国的方式而战
Yes I'm here to fight for truth and justice and the American way
你大可在美国竞选公职
You'll end up fighting every official in this country
你不是说真的吧 露意丝
You don't really mean that
- 我不相信  - 露意丝
- I don't believe this  - Lois
我不说谎的
I never lie
你能飞多快？
How fast do you fly by the way?
我真的不知道 我没有实际的去计算时间
I don't know I've never actually bothered to time myself
不知道 我说
Say
我们来了解看看？
Why don't we find out?
你提议我们怎么做？
And how do you propose we do that?
跟我飞一下 你是说我也可以飞？
Take a ride with me, You mean I could fly?
如果可以的话 我可以托着你一起飞
I'd be handling the flying if that's okay
- 那就真是太棒了  - 等等你要去哪里
- This is utterly fantastic  - Wait a minute, Where are you going?
- 你是说正经的吗？  - 当然
- Are you serious?  - Sure
怎么了？ 你不想去吗？
Don't you want to go?
好 你不需要这些
You won't need these
我需要一件毛衣 一定会冷
I need a sweater It must be kind of
不 你不会冷的
No you'll be warm enough
好了吗
Ready
克拉克说你只是人家想像的神话而已
Clark said that you were just a figment of somebody's imagination
就像小飞侠彼得潘一样
Like Peter Pan
克拉克是谁？ 你的男朋友吗？
Clark who's that? Your boyfriend?
- 克拉克 哦 没什么  - 彼得潘
- Clark No he's nothing  - Peter Pan
彼得潘在童话里 和小孩子们一起飞翔
Peter Pan flew with children Lois In a fairy tale
你看得透我的心吗
Can you read my mind
你知道你对我做的代表什么吗？
Do you know what it is that you do to me?
我不知道你是谁？
I don't know who you are?
只是一个从别的星球来的朋友
Just a friend from another star
我就像是个去学校上课的小孩
Here I am like a kid out of school
抓着上帝的手
Holding hands with a god
我是个呆子
I'm a fool
你看看我
Will you look at me
我在颤抖着
Quivering
像个颤抖的小女孩
Like a little girl shivering
你可以感觉得出来
You can see right through me
你看得透我的心吗？
Can you read my mind?
你可以猜测我心里在想什么吗？
Can you picture the things I'm thinking of?
我在想为什么你
Wondering why you are
你真是太奇妙了
all the wonderful things you are
你会飞
You can fly
飞上天际
You belong in the sky
你和我
You and I
也能心系彼此
could belong to each other
如果你需要个朋友
If you need a friend
我是你可以飞来的目标
I'm the one to fly to
如果你需要爱
If you need to be loved
我就在这里
here I am
读我的心声
Read my mind
我们忘了计算时间
We forgot to time ourselves
也许下一次
Maybe next time
你还好吗？
You okay?
晚安
Good night
真是个超人
What a super man
超人
Superman
有人在家吗？ 喂 露意丝
Anybody home?
- 嗨 我可以进来吗  - 可以
- Hi Can I come in Oh  - Yeah
露意丝 天呀 你没听到我在敲门吗？
For goodness' sake didn't you hear me knocking?
露意丝 我们约好了 记得吗？
We did have a date tonight remember?
露意丝 你还没有
You haven't been
我希望没有 我们快一点 好吗？
I should certainly hope not Well let's push off shall we?
我最好穿件外套 外头会很冷
I'd better get a coat It might be cold out
我是指我的皮包 我也要梳头
I mean I need a purse and I have to fix my hair
梳理一下
put some blusher on
露意丝
Lois
我要告诉你一些事 我
There's something I have to tell you I'm really
我是指第一次我很紧张
I was at first really nervous about tonight
但我决定要给你生命难忘的一刻
But then I decided darn it I was going to show you the time of your life
克拉克 那很不错
That's Clark nice
也许我们可以去吃个汉堡 或者你想做什么？
We could go for a hamburger or whatever you want to do?
(我与超人的一夜)
(露意丝独家访问)
告诉我
Now then
他提到那个银河系的正确位置
given the exact location of the galaxy that he mentions
还有我们太阳系
and the proximity to our own solar system
真是太奇妙
It's amazing Amazing
太奇妙了 好到不可能是真的
Too good to be true
不可能是真的 他有六尺四 黑发 蓝眼
It's too good to be true 6' 4 black hair blue eyes
不喝酒 不抽烟 只说真话
doesn't drink or smoke and tells the truth
黛丝玛克小姐 有些人可以读战争与和平
Some people can read War and Peace
而有些人认为 只是个探险故事而已
and think it was an adventure story
有些人可以了解口香糖的成分是什么
Others can read the ingredients on a gum wrapper
以及宇宙的秘密
and unlock the secrets of the universe
莱克斯 口香糖与宇宙秘密有何关连
Lex what has chewing gum got to do with the secrets of the universe
对 黛丝玛克小姐
Right Miss Teschmacher
N…
N...
M 路德先生 你需要的马上来
M You want M Mr Luthor Coming right up
M到了
So there you go M
M 好笨 欧提斯 不 不 是N
M as in moron Otis No
N 像是尼安得塔尔人的N 呆子
It's N as in Neanderthal
而L就是梯子
nincompoop nitwit and L as in ladder
梯子在这里 路德先生 马上来了
Here's a ladder coming right up
我没有看到 因为
I didn't see
对不起 路德先生
I'm sorry Mr Luthor
在访问时他说克普顿星球
In the interview he says that the Planet Krypton
在1948年爆炸
exploded in 1948
这个荒谬的人
That ridiculous little freak
花了三年搭太空船来到这里
took three years in a rocket to get to earth
因此
Ergo Ergo
1948年 三年
Ergo 1948 that's three years on
他是六尺四 你知道的？
He's 6' 4 you know that?
你知道为什么200 对我们两个这么重要？
Do you know why the number 200 is so vitally descriptive to both you and me?
这个数字 是你的体重 我的智商
It's your weight and my IQ
想想人们 想一想
Think people think
去除理性 是这游戏的名字
Deductive reasoning That's the name of the game
来自克普顿星球爆炸的碎片
Fragments from the Planet Krypton
进入外太空
exploded and went into outer space
有些东西也掉到地球
It is reasonable to assume
这是很合理的
that some of those particles of debris drifted to Earth
陨石
Meteorites
答对了
Jawohl
找到了
Voila
陨石掉在阿迪斯阿贝巴
A meteorite found in Addis Ababa
我知道我很多嘴 但是
I know I'll get rapped in the mouth for this but
这又如何呢？
so what?
又如何？ 你是指它们只是陨石而已
So what You mean to us? they're just meteorites
说得好
Fair enough
但是那种特别的 辐射线很高
But the level of specific radioactivity
以至于来自克普顿星球的东西
is so high to anyone from the Planet Krypton
就是致命的
this substance is lethal
等一下 路德先生
Wait a minute Mr Luthor
你是说即使火和子弹也伤不了他
Fire and bullets can't hurt this guy
这个东西
but this stuff here
会要他的命
will kill him
是的
yes
你有没有一种
Doesn't it give you a kind of
和我在同一个房间里突然有感觉
a shudder of electricity
像被电流穿过一样吗
through you to be in the same room with me
不是电流 除非你想打那陨石的主意
Not like the shudder you'll get when you lay that rock on him
不过从数里外 用千里眼就会看到你了
He can see you coming for miles with those super peepers of his
天呀 你给他们眼睛 但他们却看不到
O Lord you gave them eyes but they cannot see
超人无法透视铅
nor can Superman through lead
他看不透铅
He can't see through lead
氪石会毁了他
And Kryptonite will destroy him
还有问题吗？
Any questions class?
我怀疑它们为什么会掉在阿迪斯阿贝巴
I wonder what they're wearing in Addis Ababa
看起来像个阿拉伯人
Looks like a burnoose
用布围起来
It's just a wraparound
有24K的黄金 不是18K
lt's 24 karat not 18 karat gold
我们要去阿迪斯阿贝巴 路德先生
Are we going to Addis Ababa Mr Luthor
母鸟对飞弹导航
Mother Bird to Missile Convoy over
飞弹导航对母鸟 继续
Missile Convoy to Mother Bird go ahead
每件事看起来都很好 基地见 完毕
Everything looks good see you at the base Over and out
收到 母鸟 完毕
Roger Mother Bird Over and out
看看这个
Look at this
看起来很糟
Looks pretty bad
你认为她死了吗？
Think she's dead?
试试脉搏
Take her pulse
快用呼叫器请救护车
Get an ambulance down here
我可不想因此延误护航
I don't want to hold this convoy up more than I have to
她的呼吸有困难 你认为呢？
She's having trouble breathing What do you think?
我建议作胸部按摩
I suggest a vigorous chest massage
如果没用 就口对口
If that doesn't work mouthtomouth
中士
Yes sir
我可不要我的人 做那种我自己也不想做的事
I won't have my men do anything I wouldn't be prepared to do myself
是 但是 长官
Yeah but sir
叫救护车
Get an ambulance
好了 大家集合起来
Gather around
向后转
Turn around
(救护车)
嗨
Hi
有人受伤吗？
Somebody hurt?
我做到了 路德先生 黛丝玛克小姐
I did it Mr Luthor
我成功了
Miss Teschmacher I did it
正如你吩咐的 很好 欧提斯 很好
Just like you told me All right Otis
好 欧提斯 不是我不信任你
It isn't that I don't trust you but
但我不信任你 你做了什么？
I don't trust you Otis What did you do?
我把第一个
I set the first directional vector
无线电接到38
to 38
第二个到67 第三个到117
The second one to 67 And the third one to 117
第四个呢？
What about the fourth one?
第四个
What fourth one
等等 第三到117
Wait a minute The third one to 117
是的 我写下来了 路德先生 我写下
Yes See I wrote it down, Mr Luthor.
欧提斯 欧提斯
Otis,Otis.
第三个应该是11 第四个是7
The third one was supposed to be 11 and the fourth one 7
天啊 路德先生
Oh gee Mr Luthor
我想我的手臂不够长
I guess my arm wasn't long enough see
你想看看长手臂吗？
Would you like to see a long arm?
欧提斯 你想看看长长的手臂吗？
Otis would you like to see a very very long arm?
欧提斯 欧提斯
Oh no Mr Luthor
不路德先生
No Mr Luthor
- 好 这次要做对  - 是的 路德先生
- All right Get it right  - Yes Mr Luthor
麦当劳 我以为你告诉我 这条路已经封锁了
MacDonald I thought you told me this road would be blocked off
杰柏斯基 我不是告诉你
Jablowsky didn't I tell you
麦当劳 我不是问他 我是问你
I didn't asked him I asked you
好 跟我来 老兄
All right Follow me men
退 把车往后退 把车往后退
Back that thing off the road Back it off the road
你要不要回头 退到路边去
You fellas get back into that thing and back it off the road
等一下会有护卫队过来
We got a convoy coming through here
听着 你们要绕个圆圈回来 我没时间跟你辩
You'll have to circle back I don't have time to argue
真是倒霉的日子 不是吗？
It's a heck of a day isn't it?
我们转错弯了 我们在找12号道
We took the wrong turn We were looking for Route 12
- 12号道 这是后面 不是吗？  - 不 长官 是上面
- Route 12 That's back there  - No sir it's up there
中士 我们转错了
Sergeant we took the wrong road
我是少尉 你是在跟长官讲话
I'm a Lieutenant A Naval Officer
- 住口  - 从12号道转回去
- Shut up  - Now Route 12 is back that way
美国 海军
This man is a diabetic you see
你知道我的报社对此事非常的有兴趣
As you know the Daily Planet is very interested in that dam
但我不懂的是
but what I don't understand
你为何要卖给一个未曾谋面的人
is why you'd sell out to a faceless person you've never met
你连他的名字都不知道 啊 是
You don't know his name
他肯付那么高的价钱
At the stupid high price he offered
买这片没有价值的沙漠
for this worthless piece of desert
我希望那是值得的
I hope it's Custer
太棒了 这就是我要的 谢谢
Perfect just what I need Thank you
从弹着点为你报导
Reporting live from the launch site ground zero
今天真是历史性的一天
Today marks a historic occasion since
因为两枚XK101火箭 就要同时发射
two XK101 rockets will be launched simultaneously
一枚是陆军 一枚是海军
One by the Army and one by the Navy
嗨 各位 今天有没有看到露意丝？
Hi,everybody,Has anybody seen Lois today?
不 我没有 但老编想见你
No but the Chief wants to see you
你挡到我们了 克拉克
You're blocking the set Clark
对不起 吉儿 茱蒂今天好吗？
Sorry Gil How's Judy today Okay?
很好
Good
进来 肯特
Come in Kent
对不起 白先生
Excuse me Mr White
你想见我？ 你看到露意丝吗？
You wanted to see me sir? Have you seen Lois today?
她出城到西部 去了解一笔土地诈欺交易
She's out West looking into a landfraud deal
我派欧森陪她一起去 第一次的任务
I sent young Olsen with her on his first assignment
有点不是很明确 有人出了不可思议的
Some unidentified clown is buying thousands of acres
价钱去买一片沙漠
of worthless desert at incredible prices
天呀 好像没什么道理
That doesn't seem to make sense
这世界本来就没啥道理
The world doesn't make sense
肯特 你现在应该晓得了
You ought to know that
你去看看从阿迪斯阿贝巴来的文件
Look at this dispatch from Addis Ababa
有人闯进博物馆 在寂静的夜晚杀了两个人
People break into a museum at night kill two people
他们拿了什么
and what do they take
一件毫无价值的陨石 你觉得怎样 白先生
A worthless piece of meteorite How do you figure that
我一直不能明白暴力的形式
I've never been able to understand violence
我知道你 肯特
I know that about you
也是我想跟你谈的原因
That's why I wanted to talk to you
我已在新闻界待四十年了
I've been in this news game 40 years man and boy
在这里 我有胆识 有同情 有耐性
and I got where I am with guts compassion
还有一些是你没有的
elbow grease and something you're sadly lacking in son
谦卑
Humility
不 不是谦卑 你有太多谦卑了
Not humility you've got bags of humility
侵略性 自信心 这是关键
Aggression confidence that's the ticket
拿主导权吧 让人们知道你是谁吧
Take charge Let people know who you are
为什么我不是年轻十岁
Why l wasn't a boy 10 years
让大家知道我是谁
Let people know who l am
我是莱克斯路德
This is Lex Luthor
少于四只脚的 能听到这个的
Only one thing alive with less than four legs can hear this frequency
只有你 超人
That's you
大约只需五分钟 一种有毒的瓦斯弹
In five minutes a poisoned gas pellet
包含着丙烷元素的混合物
containing propane lithium compound
释放出上千个粒子 在本市的上空中
will be released through thousands of air ducts in this city
将会消灭一半的大都会人口
effectively annihilating half the population of Metropolis
在我大部分朋友还是影印小弟时 我就是记者了
I was a reporter before most of my friends were copy boys
这也是我要你做的原因 叫露意丝帮你介绍给超人
I want you to get Lois to introduce you to Superman
找出他是谁？他长什么样子？他哪来的蓝衣服？
Find out who he is? Where did he get that blue suit?
在何时做的 是丝的吗？ 还是塑胶的
Did he have it made Is it silk? Is it plastic?
我知道好像有点不合情理
I know it all seems a bit much
但我怎么去见你 超人
but how else was I going to meet you Superman
我知道你不会接受一场茶会的邀请
I knew you'd never accept an invitation to tea
但有一件不幸的灾难
But a disaster with people
人们陷入危险中 他们需要帮助
in danger people who need help
我知道你不会放过这个插手的机会
I just knew you couldn't resist that chance to sort of pitch in
你知道我的意思吗？
You know what I mean?
是超人
lt's Superman
看 我的天
Look Oh my God
你是很强壮 超人
There's a strong streak of good in you Superman
但没有人是完美的
But then nobody's perfect
几乎没有
Almost nobody
真是个 哦 超人
Oh Superman Gee
天 站回去
GeeStand back please Stand back
请站回去 可以了 没什么值得忧心的
Stand back please Nothing to get worried about
不要像个大傻瓜一样 快出去
Don't sit there like a numskull get out
你看看那个长太大的童军 黛丝玛克小姐
Look at that overgrown boy scout Miss Teschmacher
告诉我你看到了什么？
Tell me what you see?
可爱 酒窝
Cuteness dimples
你喜欢可爱 嗯
You like cuteness
酒窝
Dimples
我就给你酒窝
I'll give you dimples
压力还是在你身上
The pressure is still on you
超人 你知道他们说 怕热
You know they say: If you can't stand the heat
就别进厨房
get out of the tunnel
这是你最后一次机会 超人
It's your last chance Superman
你何不帮帮自己 冷冻起来
Why don't you do yourself a favor and freeze
我想他来了 路德先生
I think he's coming Mr Luthor
(危险致命)
他铁定是来了 路德先生
He's definitely coming
门开着 请进
It's open come in
律师先生会跟你联络有关于门被损坏一事
My attorney will be in touch with you about the damage to the door
Otis take the gentleman's cape
我觉得他不会愿意让我拿
I don't think he wants me to
路德先生 瓦斯弹在哪里
Where's the gas pellet
在某个地方
Somewhere
事实上 在我心中
It's in the back of my mind actually
这是一个小主意 我只是开个玩笑
It's a little idea I was toying with
你想得出这种把戏 真是头脑坏了
Is that how a warped brain like yours gets its kicks
你这样为无辜的人们设计死亡
By planning the death of innocent people
不 不是引起无辜人们的死亡
No By causing the death of innocent people
发射
Fire
蓝鸟 发射成功
Navy Bird we have a good launch
海军XK101
Navy missile XK101
攻击完美
Angle of attack is perfect
爬升得很快 水压 正常
Climbing fast Hydraulics general function
你也许知道 也许不知道
As you may or may not know I am as they say
我有很多的土地
very heavy into real estate
而且为了赚钱 你就必须低价买高价卖 对吗
To make money you have to buy for a little and sell for a lot right
对
Right
所以问题是
So the problem
如何在你买土地及卖掉它之前
How to make the land more valuable between the time you buy it
让你的土地更有价值
and the time you sell it
这是加州
Now this is California
最有钱 最受欢迎的州
The richest most populous state in the Union
我不需要你教我地理课
I don't need a geography lesson from you
我忘了 你已经去过了
Of course you've been there I do forget you get around don't you
我讲到哪里了？
Where was I?
加州
California California right
加州圣安德烈断层 你应该听过
The San Andreas Fault maybe you've heard of it
是的 是关于两块土地连接在一起
Yes It's the joining together of two land masses
错误的线 不稳定也常移动
The fault line is shifting
那是因为加州常常地震的缘故
which is why you get earthquakes in California
好极了 比我说的还好
Wonderful Couldn't have said it better myself
圣安德烈断层
Everything west of this line is the richest
这条线以西就是世界上不动产最贵的地方
most expensive real estate in the world
圣地牙哥 洛杉矶 三藩市
San Diego Los Angeles San Francisco
在这条线这边的一切
Everything on this side of the line
就是绵延几千里的没有价值的沙漠土地
is just hundreds of miles of worthless desert land
刚好是
which just happens to be owned by
路德先生所拥有的
Lex Luthor Incorporated
叫我呆子 说我不负责吧
Now call me foolish call me irresponsible
但对我而言 五百万顿的炸药
It occurs to me that a 500megaton bomb
放在合适的地点
planted at just the proper point would
会毁掉加州的大部分
Would destroy most of California
数以百万无辜的人都会被杀害
Millions of people would be killed
连西海岸 你知道的
and the West Coast as we know it would
也将会沉到海底 再见 加州
Fall into the sea Byebye California
哈啰 新西海岸 我的西海岸
Hello new West Coast My West Coast
(莱克斯海岸)
莱克斯海岸 路德村
Costa Del Lex Luthorville
莱克斯码头 欧提斯堡
Marina Del Lex Otisburg
欧提斯堡?
Otisburg?
黛丝玛克小姐的 她家就在那儿
Miss Teschmacher she's got her own place
欧提斯堡
Otisburg
只是一个小地方
It's a little bitty place
欧提斯堡
Otisburg
好 我就把它擦掉 只是个小城镇
I'll just wipe it off that's all
你是个梦想家 莱克斯路德
You're a dreamer Lex Luthor
变态的作梦专家 你的计划不可能会成功的
A sick twisted dreamer Your plan couldn't possibly work
我承认仍有一些问题
I'll admit there were a few problems
仍要调整一下飞弹的轨道
Adjusting the precise trajectory of the missile
需要找到最重要的点发射
Finding the optimum stress point for the fault line itself
顺便 目标点 就在
which by the way is target zero Right
这里
here
不可能
That's impossible
到底发生什么事？ 中士
What's happening Lieutenant?
飞出轨道了 先生
Trajectory malfunction sir
是 长官
Yes sir
那么就放弃
Abort
没有功能 长官
Function negative sir
你不能打下来吗
Can't you knock them down
绝对不可能 他们有新P20的低回避系统
Absolutely impossible sir They have the new P20 lowlevel avoidance systems
给我接五角大厦
Get me the Pentagon
你认为如何 超级小孩 有趣吗
What do you think super baby Interesting
你的理论令人印象深刻 路德
Your theory's quite impressive Luthor
欧提斯 你去观察室一下
Would you go to the viewing room please
但至于其他的 没什么 只是变态的幻想而已
But as for the rest it's nothing but a sick fantasy
幻想
Fantasy
不 不
No
已经发生了 超人
It's history It's happening Superman
黛丝玛克小姐
Miss Teschmacher
是的 莱克斯
Yes Lex
火箭在哪里？
Where's the rocket now?
就好像越过大峡谷的蝙蝠 另一枚也是一样
It's going like a bat over the Grand Canyon so is the other one
另一枚
The other one
有两枚
There are two of them
是的 超人有双重危机
Yes Superman double jeopardy
即使你再快 也无法阻止两枚
Even you with your great speed couldn't stop both of them
我 另一方面 我可以用我的引爆器来阻止
While I on the other hand could stop them with my detonator
好 路德 在哪里？
All right Luthor where is it?
引爆器在哪？
Where's the detonator?
你有病 疯子
Diseased maniac
你真的认为可以藏在铅里面 让我找不到吗？
Do you think you could hide it from me by encasing it in lead?
我会把这盒子当作囚禁你的笼子
I'll mold this box into your prison bars
不要碰它
Don't touch that
我告诉过你
I told you
是氪石 超人
It's Kryptonite
从古老家乡来的纪念品
A little souvenir from your hometown
我不花一毛钱就可以使你觉得像在家
I've spared no expense to make you feel at home
你是很厉害 超人
You were great in your day
不过应该是
But it just stands to reason
要收拾你的时候了
when it came time to cash in your chips
这位老而有病的疯子将成为你的主宰
this old diseased maniac would be your banker
小心肌肉过度紧绷
Mind over muscle
你一点也不在意另一枚飞弹的方向 对吧？
You don't even care where the other missile's headed do you?
我当然在意
Certainly I do
我知道它正确的方位
I know exactly where it's headed
赫肯色 纽泽西
Hackensack New Jersey
我现在必须要走了 不要伤心 我们都会有错
I have to leave you now No hard feelings We all have our little faults
我的在加州
Mine's in California
莱克斯 我母亲住在赫肯色
Lex my mother lives in Hackensack
(下层包裹运送区)
黛丝玛克小姐
Miss Teschmacher
两枚都失去控制 无法重新设定
Both birds uncontrolled lmpossible to reset
欧提斯
Otis
黛丝玛克小姐
Miss Teschmacher
拜托
Please you can't
你不能光站在那儿
you can't just stand there
你不能就站在那儿让数百万无辜的人死去
You can't just stand and let millions of innocent people die
也许
Maybe
拜托 请帮助我去救他们
Please Please help me to save them
如果我帮助你 你会答应先救我妈妈吗？
Would you promise to save my mother first?
但露意丝 吉米
But Lois and Jimmy
哦 我母亲先
But my mother comes first
如果你答应我 我就相信你 因为你从不说谎
If you promise I'll believe you because you always tell the truth
我答应 我答应
I promise I promise
你为何先吻我
Why did you kiss me first
我觉得你待会儿不会让我吻你
I didn't think you'd let me later
谢谢你 黛丝玛克小姐
Thank you Miss Teschmacher
为什么我就是找不到好人？
Why is it I can't get it on with the good guys?
站一边去 我要快一点了
Stand aside now I wouldn't stay here either
陆军战鸟仍往东飞
Army Bird still heading due east
海军战鸟仍在往西飞
Navy Bird still heading due west
失去雷达接触
Losing radar contact
下次雷达接触是在三秒钟
Next radar contact after three seconds
两只鸟雷达都有接触
intercept both birds
(汽油)
陆军战鸟仍往东飞
Army Bird still headed east sir
陆军战鸟射入空中
Army Bird gaining altitude
黛丝玛克小姐 直往上爬
Miss Teschmacher We have straight climb
雷达接触增强
Radar contact strong
黛丝玛克小姐
Miss Teschmacher
雷达报告 海军战鸟在圣安德烈区
Radar report Navy Bird San Andreas area
往下降 15秒钟后撞击
Navy bird heading down 15 seconds to impact
海军战鸟往下飞 15秒钟后撞击
Navy Bird heading down 15 seconds to impact
15秒开始计时
15 seconds and counting
撞击圣安德烈断层 天啊
lmpact: San Andreas God
(打烊)
(抱歉 我们打烊了)
我们插播新闻快报
We interrupt the program for a newsflash
有梅军事飞弹在南加州沙漠爆炸
A military missile has exploded in the Southern California desert
爆炸的力量已经在圣安德烈断层产生影响
The force of the explosion has activated the San Andreas fault
加州发生了很大的地震
California is suffering a major earthquake
怎么了？
What's going on?
是地震 看
It's a quake Look
小心
Look out
到巴士后面
Get to the back of the bus
好了 孩子们 没事了
Okay kids it's all right now
感谢老天 我们回到桥上了
Thank God we're back on the bridge
是超人
Hey it's Superman
lt's Superman
天啊
Holy mackerel
我们完了
We're going off the tracks
抓紧
Hang on
我煞不住车
l can't hold her
所有的人撤离水坝
All personnel evacuate dam
All personnel evacuate the dam
小心电苐线
Watch that cable
我看不到了
找人想办法切断电源
Someone try and pull the main
不可能 太烫了
It's impossible It's red hot
大家都还好吗
Is that man all right
是
Yeah
抓好 吉米
Hang on Jim
水坝破了
The dam broke
别管车了 快点
Forget the car Come on come on
你在这里会很安全的 孩子
You're safe here son
我还好 雷恩小姐等一下就开车来了
That's okay Miss Lane will be driving by any minute
来乔治 来 开上山坡
Come on Make it to the hill
南加州的地震损失惨重
There has been major quake damage to Southern California
圣安德烈断层奇迹似的回复了
The San Andreas fault has miraculously sealed itself
但南加州仍因地震遭到强烈的损失
Yet Southern California is suffering an aftershock of a major earthquake
人们仍要警觉
The population is still warned to be aware
快点 启动
Please come on turn over
有些地方还是
which in some areas has
快点
Come on
救我 救我
Help me Help me please
露意丝
Lois
喔 我的天
No no no
不 不 不
不 不
No no
我的儿子
My son
你不得干涉人类的历史
It is forbidden for you to interfere
我只知道一件事 你来这里必有原因
There's one thing I do know Son and that is you are here for a reason
但你不得干涉人类的历史 我能做很多事 但
lt is forbidden for you to interfere Those things l can do
被禁止的
It is forbidden
我竟然无法救她
but I couldn't even save him
是被禁止的
lt is forbidden
被禁止的
It is forbidden
嗨
Hi
不要再试了 我想没用了
Don't bother it's dead
确定没用了
Sure it's dead
麻烦的事情是一件接着一件
The problem with men of steel is they're never around when you want one
你知道我发生什么事吗 当你飞走的时候
Do you know what happened while you were off flying around
我几乎陷入地震中 在我的车子旁边
I was almost in an earthquake
一个汽油站爆炸了
A gas station blew up beside my car
电线杆倾倒在路边 我几乎濒临死亡之际时
Telephone poles falling all over the road I was almost killed
车子的汽油却用完了
To top the whole thing off this stupid car runs out of gas
我很难过 露意丝
I'm sorry about that Lois
但我一直很忙
But I've been kind of busy for a while
我很抱歉 没事了
I'm sorry that's all right
非常谢谢你 超人
Thanks a lot Superman
在地震时 你为我铺了一条生路
Put me in the middle of nowhere during an earthquake
在没有食物 没有水 而蛇到处乱爬的情况下
No food no water snakes everywhere
我实在不知道你是否会回来
I had no idea if you were coming back
有件事我得去做 再见了
There's something I have to do I'll see you later
他不能留一下下吗
He can't stay still for a second
天啊 雷恩小姐 可惜肯特先生看不到这一幕
Golly Miss Lane it's too bad Mr Kent wasn't here to see all this
可怜的克拉克 每次超人在时 他都不在
Yeah poor Clark He's never around when
克拉克等一等
Clark Wait a minute
等一等
Wait a minute
什么
What
露意丝雷恩 这是最笨的想法
Lois Lane that is the silliest idea
我告诉你一件事 雷恩小姐 我想他真的很关心你
I'll tell you something Miss Lane I think he really cares about you
- 克拉克 他当然是  - 不 不是克拉克
- Clark Of course he does  - No not Clark
超人他关心所有的人
Superman cares about everybody Jimmy
谁知道 有一天 如果他幸运的话
But who knows Someday if he's lucky
你毁了我的衣服
You're messing up my suit
你这个大白痴
You big lummox you
快点 停止
Come on stop it will you
- 欧提斯  - 都是你的错 小心要着陆了
- Otis  - Watch the ground you
晚安 典狱长
Good evening Warden
我想 这两位跟你在一起会很安全的
These two men should be safe here
也可安全直到公平的审判为止
til they can get a fair trial
他是谁
Who is it Superman
莱克斯路德
Lex Luthor
- 本世纪最伟大的罪犯  - 本世纪
- The greatest criminal mind of our time  - Of our time
我在此声明 这些墙
I hereby serve notice He's serving notice to you
这些墙
that these walls
拜托 你住口 好吗
Will you shut up you fat little fool
好 把他们带走
All right take them away boys
你这个傻瓜 笨蛋
You you nitwit
警卫
Nincompoop
这个国家
This country
又安全了 谢谢你 超人
is safe again Superman thanks to you
不 先生
No sir
不必言谢 典狱长
Don't thank me Warden
我们都是同一阵线的
We're all part of the same team
晚安
Good night